Louis Lozowick
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Louis Lozowick papers
1898-1974
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Louis Lozowick
6.0 linear feet
The Louis Lozowick Papers measure 6.0 linear feet and are dated 1898-1974. Correspondence, writings, business records, printed material and photographs document Lozowick's career. Also included are biographical documents, sketches, and records relating to organizations that interested him.
Biographical Note
Louis Lozowick (1892-1973) is known for his lithographs of New York City, many in the Precisionist mode. As a very young boy in the Ukraine, Lozowick showed an aptitude for drawing. At age eleven, with an older brother, he moved from his rural hometown to Kiev, where he received training at the Kiev Art Institute. In 1906, Lozowick came to the United States, joining a brother in New Jersey. While in high school, and for several years afterwards, Lozowick studied at the National Academy of Design under Leon Kroll, George Willloughby Maynard, Ivan Olinsky, and Douglas Volk. He graduated from Ohio State University in 1918 with a degree in art.
After a year's stint in the medical corps of the U.S. Army, Lozowick headed to Paris in the fall of 1920, where he studied French at the Sorbonne. By early 1922, he had settled in Berlin and was enrolled at the Friedrick Wilhelms Universität. During this time, Lozowick began painting seriously, made his first lithographs, and established friendships with many Russian artists in Germany, including El Lissitsky; he also made a trip to Moscow, where he met a number of leading Russian artists. While living in Berlin, Lozowick had his first solo show at K. E. Twardy Book Shop in 1922, and a second at the Gallerie Alfred Heller in the following year.
Lozowick worked mainly as a graphic artist and supplemented his income with commercial work. In addition, he taught art history and lithography classes, lectured, and wrote about art. During the Depression he worked with the Public Works of Art Project, New York City, for a brief time in 1934. Between 1935 and 1940, he was employed by the Graphic Arts Division of the Works Progress Administration.
Lozowick taught art history at the Educational Alliance Art School, New York City, for a semester prior to going to Europe, and for extended periods afterwards. He was a lithography instructor at the John Reed Club School of Art and the American Artists School, and over the years taught a number of private pupils. In 1924, Lozowick delivered lectures on modern Russian art for the Société Anonyme, and lectured regularly on a variety of art topics to a many other groups. Eventually he was represented by a speakers' bureau that arranged several lecture tours.
Russian art, art and artists in the Soviet Union, and Jewish art were among the topics that particularly interested Lozowick. He wrote extensively on these subjects and others, publishing many articles and reviews. While living in Berlin, he wrote for Broom and contributed translations to that periodical. Two major manuscripts, a book about William Gropper and a memoir titled Survivor From a Dead Age, appeared posthumously. In addition, he was a founder of the New Masses, a contributing editor, and eventually its art editor.
One of the organizers of the John Reed Club in 1929 and a charter member, Lozowick became its Executive Secretary in 1931 and remained active throughout the club's five-year existence. In 1935, Lozowick participated in organizing the first American Artists' Congress, became the group's Executive Secretary, and for several years was an extremely active member of the New York chapter.
Throughout his long career, Louis Lozowick exhibited widely in local and national exhibitions. He won a number of awards and was invited to spend several summers in residence at the Yaddo artists' colony.
Scope and Content Note
The Louis Lozowick Papers measure 6.0 linear feet and are dated 1898-1974. Correspondence, writings, business records, printed material and photographs document Lozowick's career. Also included are biographical documents, sketches, and records relating to organizations that interested him.
Correspondence with colleagues, commercial clients, organizations, museums and galleries, family and friends, concerns business and personal affairs. A small number of letters are in Russian, Yiddish, German, and French. Writings include manuscripts, drafts, and notes for articles, books, reviews, and talks on art related subjects and other topics. Among Lozowick's notes are seven notebooks relating to published and unpublished writings.
Business records consist of an extensive alphabetical file recording sales and consignments, loans for exhibitions, and other financial transactions, accompanied by related printed material. Originally housed in loose leaf notebooks, these files are arranged by name of gallery, museum, organization, or event. In addition, there are a small number of loose receipts.
Lozowick retained printed matter, unpublished notes and writings, and miscellaneous items relating to organizations and groups of interest to him. The American Artists' Congress and the John Reed Club files are of particular interest; because he served as an officer in these organizations, his papers include copies of minutes, reports, and official correspondence.
Printed material includes exhibition catalogs, invitations and announcements. Material by Lozowick consists of articles, reviews, illustrations and reproductions. In addition, there are articles and miscellaneous items about Lozowick including announcements of his lectures, a course syllabus, and brochure about a tour of the U.S.S.R. led by him. Miscellaneous printed material includes research materials collected by Lozowick for his writing; illustrations of artists at work, in their studios, galleries, etc., and a 1922 broadside in French and Russian announcing a lecture.
Photographs include images of Lozowick and his family. Of particular interest is a photograph of Lozowick at a 1934 demonstration sponsored by the John Reed Club and Artists' Union. Photographs of works of art include works by Lozowick, as well as by American, European, and Russian artists; many of these, including lantern slides, may have been used to illustrate his lectures and writings. Among the miscellaneous subjects are Lozowick's studio, the Soviet Pavilion at the 1939 World's Fair, and an unidentified Soviet exhibition installation.
Also included are small number of biographical documents and sketches in pen and ink.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into 8 series:
Series 1: Biographical Information, 1923-1973 (Box 1; 10 folders; Reel 5893)
Series 2: Correspondence, 1916-1974 (Boxes 1-2; 1.25 linear ft.; Reels 5893-5895)
Series 3: Writings and Notes, 1917-circa 1970 (Boxes 2-3; 1.5 linear ft.; Reels 5895-5897)
Series 4: Business Records, 1929-1973 (Box 3; 0.25 linear ft.; Reel 5897-5898)
Series 5: Organizations, 1930-1972 (Box 4; 0.4 linear ft.; Reel 5898)
Series 6: Printed Material, 1920-1974 (Boxes 4-5 and OV 7; 1.25 linear ft.; Reels 5898-5899)
Series 7: Sketches, n.d. (Box 5; 1 folder; Reel 5899)
Series 8: Photographs, 1898-1973 (Boxes 6-7; 1.25 linear ft.; Reel 5899)
Index Terms
This collection is indexed in the online catalog of the Archives of American Art under the following index terms. People, families and organizations are listed under "Names" when they are creators or contributors and under "Subjects" when they are the topic of collection contents.
Subjects:
American Artists' Congress; John Reed Club
Subjects-Topical:
Lithographers -- New York (State) -- New York
Types of Materials:
Photographs; Sketches; Writings
Provenance
Gift of Louis and Adele Lozowick, 1966-1980. Various portions were microfilmed on reels D254-D254A, and 1333-1337. In 2004, all portions of the gift were merged, reprocessed, and remicrofilmed.
Restrictions on Access
The microfilm of this collection has been digitized and is available online via AAA's website. Use of material not microfilmed or digitized requires an appointment.
Alternative Forms Available
The microfilm of this collection was digitized in 2007 and is available via the Archives of American Art's website.
Series Descriptions/Container Listing
- Biographical Information, 1923-1973, Series 1:; (Box 1; 10 folders; Reel 5893)
  - Autobiographical Notes, 1943, 1973, n.d. (Box 1, Reel 5893, Frame 11-25)
  - Awards, 1965-1973, n.d. (Box 1, Reel 5893, Frame 26-37)
  - Biographical Notes, 1936-1960s, n.d. (Box 1, Reel 5893, Frame 38-59)
  - Certificate of Naturalization (copy of original issued October 21, 1919), 1944 (Box 1, Reel 5893, Frame 60-61)
  - European Correspondent Credentials, Union Bulletin, Cincinnati, 1923 (Box 1, Reel 5893, Frame 62-63)
  - List of WPA Prints by Lozowick Owned by New York Public Library, 1943 (Box 1, Reel 5893, Frame 64-65)
  - Membership Cards, 1932-1973, n.d. (Box 1, Reel 5893, Frame 66-82)
  - Miscellaneous Items (business cards; travel itineraries), 1959-1962, n.d. (Box 1, Reel 5893, Frame 83-91)
  - Questionnaires (Artists for Victory; Who's Who in the Jewish Social Registry; Federal Support for the Visual Arts), 1943-1968 (Box 1, Reel 5893, Frame 92-116)
- Correspondence, 1916-1974, Series 2:; (Boxes 1-2; 1.25 linear ft.; Reels 5893-5895)
  This series consists mainly of incoming letters, though a smaller number of replies and outgoing letters have survived among the papers. Correspondence with colleagues, commercial clients, organizations, museums and galleries, family and friends documents Lozowick's business and personal affairs including: Lozowick's writings, exhibitions, loans and sales of artwork, requests and arrangements for lectures, the Works Progress Administration, news of friends, and the activities of artists' and political organizations of interest to Lozowick. A small number of letters are in Russian, Yiddish, German, and French.
  Among Lozowick's correspondents are Peter Blume, Paul Burlin, Marc Chagall, Malcolm Crowley, Mrs. Chester Dale, Theodore Dreiser, Lewis Mumford, Richard Neutra, Man Ray, Meyer Schapiro, and Art Young. Letters to his wife and son include a number of illustrations.
  In addition, small amount of official correspondence of the American Artists' Congress and the John Reed Club is filed with Series 5: Organizations.
  - Correspondence, 1916-1931, (17 folders) (Box 1, Reel 5893, Frame 118-385)
  - Correspondence, 1932-1935, (17 folders) (Box 1, Reel 5893, Frame 386-779)
  - Correspondence, 1936-1939, (17 folders) (Box 2, Reel 5893, Frame 780-1149)
  - Correspondence, 1940-1945, (17 folders) (Box 2, Reel 5893, Frame 1150-1427)
  - Correspondence, 1946-1950, (12 folders) (Box 2, Reel 5894, Frame 13-310)
  - Correspondence, 1951-1955, (12 folders) (Box 2, Reel 5894, Frame 311-596)
  - Correspondence, 1956-1959, (12 folders) (Box 2, Reel 5894, Frame 597-906)
  - Correspondence, 1960-1962, (8 folders) (Box 2, Reel 5894, Frame 908-1160)
  - Correspondence, 1963-1967, (8 folders) (Box 2, Reel 5894, Frame 1161-1458)
  - Correspondence, 1968-1973, (6 folders) (Box 2, Reel 5895, Frame 12-540)
  - Condolence Letters, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Reel 5895, Frame 541-615)
  - A-Z, and Unidentified, n.d., (3 folders) (Box 2, Reel 5895, Frame 616-901)
- Writings, 1917-circa 1970, Series 3:; (Boxes 2-3; 1.5 linear ft.; Reels 5895-5897)
  Lozowick published many articles, book and exhibition reviews, and a book, Modern Russian Art. Two major works -- a book on William Gropper and a memoir titled Survivor From a Dead Age -- were published posthumously. In addition, there is evidence of a few unpublished books about art (probably unfinished). Russian art and art and artists in the Soviet Union are the focus of many articles.
  This series includes manuscripts, drafts, and notes for a wide range of writings. They are arranged by record type: articles, books, notes, and miscellaneous writings. Among the manuscripts identified as "articles" are several pieces that could be chapters for planned books or texts of classroom lectures, i.e., articles titled with names of art schools, periods, or movements, such as "Cubism," "Futurism," and "Renaissance," or places like "Greece," and "The Orient".
  Seven notebooks and loose notes relate mainly to his published and unpublished writings. Also among his notes are names, addresses and phone numbers, reminders and lists; notes on specific topics include lithography, Soviet and Russian art and artists, India and Japan. Series 6: Printed Material, includes some research materials for Lozowick's writings.
  This series is arranged into 2 subseries:
  3.1: By Lozowick
  3.2: By Other Authors
  - By Lozowick, 1917-circa 1970, 3.1:
    - Articles (Box 2, Reel 5895)
      - "The Americanization of Art," (incomplete), 1917 (Box 2, Reel 5895, Frame 904-905)
      - "The Architecture of Samarcand," n.d. (Box 2, Reel 5895, Frame 906-916)
      - "Art Today," n.d. (Box 2, Reel 5895, Frame 917-931)
      - "The Artist and His Keep," n.d. (Box 2, Reel 5895, Frame 932-937)
      - "The Artist's Community, Moscow," n.d. (Box 2, Reel 5895, Frame 938-942)
      - "The Artist's House in Moscow," n.d. (Box 2, Reel 5895, Frame 943-950)
      - "Buzkashi--Goat Ripping," n.d. (Box 2, Reel 5895, Frame 951-957)
      - "Cézanne," n.d. (Box 2, Reel 5895, Frame 958-984)
      - "Chana Orloff," n.d. (Box 2, Reel 5895, Frame 985-988)
      - "Constructivism," n.d. (Box 2, Reel 5895, Frame 989-1005)
      - "The Cubists," n.d. (Box 2, Reel 5895, Frame 1006-1034)
      - "Dura-Europos," n.d. (Box 2, Reel 5895, Frame 1035-1057)
      - "Ephraim Mikhael," 1921 (Box 2, Reel 5895, Frame 1058-1076)
      - "Expressionism," n.d. (Box 2, Reel 5895, Frame 1077-1100)
      - "Expressionism (Kandinsky)," n.d. (Box 2, Reel 5895, Frame 1101-1106)
      - "Futurism," n.d. (Box 2, Reel 5895, Frame 1107-1128)
      - "The Great Unknown," n.d. (Box 2, Reel 5895, Frame 1129-1137)
      - "Greece," n.d. (Box 2, Reel 5895, Frame 1138-1198)
      - "Honore Daumier (1808-1879)," 1928 (Box 2, Reel 5895, Frame 1199-1204)
      - "Ikonography," n.d. (Box 2, Reel 5895, Frame 1205-1213)
      - "Impressionism," n.d. (Box 2, Reel 5895, Frame 1214-1247)
      - "Industry of Socialism (The Status of the Artist in the Soviet Union)," n.d. (Box 2, Reel 5895, Frame 1248-1257)
      - "The Jew in Art," n.d. (Box 2, Reel 5895, Frame 1258-1327)
      - "Kandinsky," n.d. (Box 2, Reel 5895, Frame 1328-1342)
      - "Karl Marx on Art," n.d. (Box 2, Reel 5895, Frame 1343-1357)
      - "Lissitsky's 'Reminiscences,'" n.d. (Box 2, Reel 5895, Frame 1358-1363)
      - "Lithography: Abstraction and Realism," 1930 (Box 2, Reel 5895, Frame 1364-1368)
      - "Machine Ornament," 1929 (Box 2, Reel 5895, Frame 1369-1371)
      - "Marc Chagall," n.d. (Box 2, Reel 5895, Frame 1372-1382)
      - "Medieval Artists' Guilds," n.d. (Box 2, Reel 5895, Frame 1383-1411)
      - "Modern 19th Century," n.d. (Box 2, Reel 5895, Frame 1412-1431)
      - "Moise Kisling," 1928 (Box 2, Reel 5895, Frame 1432-1438)
      - "Mordecai Gorelik," n.d. (Box 2, Reel 5895, Frame 1439-1446)
      - "N. & S. Yefimov, Soviet Puppetteers (sic)," n.d. (Box 2, Reel 5895, Frame 1447-1452)
      - "1905 in Literature and Art," n.d. (Box 2, Reel 5896, Frame 13-102)
      - "A Note on Soviet Art," n.d. (Box 2, Reel 5896, Frame 103-105)
      - "The Orient," n.d. (Box 2, Reel 5896, Frame 106-206)
      - "Otto Schneid," n.d. (Box 2, Reel 5896, Frame 207-214)
      - "Paris Letter," n.d. (Box 2, Reel 5896, Frame 215-224)
      - "Peasant Painting," n.d. (Box 2, Reel 5896, Frame 225-231)
      - "Present Moment in Soviet Art," n.d. (Box 2, Reel 5896, Frame 232-234)
      - "Raphael Soyer," n.d. (Box 2, Reel 5896, Frame 235-238)
      - "Renaissance," n.d. (Box 2, Reel 5896, Frame 239-338)
      - "Ryback," n.d. (Box 2, Reel 5896, Frame 339-342)
      - "Solomon Nunes Carvalho," n.d. (Box 3, Reel 5896, Frame 344-439)
      - "Soviet Art," n.d. (Box 3, Reel 5896, Frame 440-446)
      - "Soviet Art in Peace and War," n.d. (Box 3, Reel 5896, Frame 447-459)
      - "Soviet Art Today (or Aspects of Soviet Art)," 1935 (Box 3, Reel 5896, Frame 460-470)
      - "Soviet Frontiers," n.d. (Box 3, Reel 5896, Frame 471-482)
      - "Soviet Graphic Art," n.d. (Box 3, Reel 5896, Frame 483-489)
      - "Temple," n.d. (Box 3, Reel 5896, Frame 490-497)
      - "Tentative Attitudes," 1917 (Box 3, Reel 5896, Frame 498-500)
      - "Towards a Revolutionary Art," 1936 (Box 3, Reel 5896, Frame 501-508)
      - "Tradition in Soviet Art," n.d. (Box 3, Reel 5896, Frame 509-527)
      - "Veritism," n.d. (Box 3, Reel 5896, Frame 528-550)
      - "What Has Been Happening in American Art?" n.d. (Box 3, Reel 5896, Frame 551-556)
      - Untitled (Box 3, Reel 5896)
        - On Art and Artists in the Soviet Union (very fragmentary), n.d., (more than one text) (Box 3, Reel 5896, Frame 557-623)
        - On Artists in the Soviet Union, n.d. (Box 3, Reel 5896, Frame 624-659)
        - On Cubism, n.d. (Box 3, Reel 5896, Frame 660-682)
        - On Drawing, n.d., (more than one text) (Box 3, Reel 5896, Frame 683-698)
        - On the Importance of Biro-Bidjan in the Lives of Jew, n.d. (Box 3, Reel 5896, Frame 699-701)
        - On Modern Art, n.d., (more than one text) (Box 3, Reel 5896, Frame 702-747)
      - Fragments, n.d. (Box 3, Reel 5896, Frame 748-755)
    - Books (Box 3, Reel 5896)
      - Memoir [published posthumously as Survivor from a Dead Age, 1997] (Box 3, Reel 5896)
        - "Chapter IX: Paris," n.d. (Box 3, Reel 5896, Frame 756-791)
        - "Chapter X: Berlin," n.d. (Box 3, Reel 5896, Frame 792-828)
        - "Chapter XI: Moscow," n.d. (Box 3, Reel 5896, Frame 829-863)
      - William Gropper (Box 3, Reel 5896)
        - Manuscript, circa 1970 (Box 3, Reel 5896, Frame 864-914)
        - Drafts and Revisions (some incomplete), n.d. (Box 3, Reel 5896, Frame 915-1102)
    - Miscellaneous Writings (Box 3, Reel 5896)
      - Book Prospectus, Picasso and Modern Art, n.d. (Box 3, Reel 5896, Frame 1103-1105)
      - Book Reviews, n.d. (Box 3, Reel 5896, Frame 1106-1171)
      - Exhibition Reviews, 1940s, n.d. (Box 3, Reel 5896, Frame 1172-1180)
      - Lecture, "A Fascist World and Freedom of Expression" (delivered at Expression in Art conference, Hotel Commodore, New York City, June 27), 1941 (Box 3, Reel 5896, Frame 1181-1191)
      - Outline for Plastic Arts (Including Architecture), n.d. (Box 3, Reel 5896, Frame 1192-1206)
      - Prefaces and Introductions to Several Unidentified Texts, n.d. (Box 3, Reel 5896, Frame 1207-1254)
    - Notes (Box 3, Reel 5896)
      - Notebooks (Box 3, Reel 5896)
        - Vol. 1: Biographical Notes on William Gropper; Vol. 2: Notes on William Gropper's Mural, n.d. (Box 3, Reel 5896, Frame 1255-1301)
        - Vol. 3 and Vol. 4: Demons, Bulgakov and Picasso (partly in Russian), n.d. (Box 3, Reel 5896, Frame 1302-1371)
        - Vol. 5: Notes on Lithography, South America, and Classification of Prints; also, Drafts of a few Letters, n.d. (Box 3, Reel 5896, Frame 1372-1403)
        - Vol. 6: Notes on Etching and Related Subjects; also, Drafts of a few Letters (partly in Russian), n.d. (Box 3, Reel 5896, Frame 1404-1435)
        - Vol. 7: Notes on the History and Construction of Synagogues (partly in Russian), n.d. (Box 3, Reel 5897, Frame 12-65)
      - Addresses, Phone Numbers, etc., n.d. (Box 3, Reel 5897, Frame 66-107)
      - Lists of Reproductions, Illustrations, etc., n.d. (Box 3, Reel 5897, Frame 108-127)
      - Notes for Article on Soviet Artists, with Related Research Material, 1940s, n.d. (Box 3, Reel 5897, Frame 128-219)
      - Notes on India and Japan, n.d. (Box 3, Reel 5897, Frame 220-268)
      - Notes on Lithography, n.d. (Box 3, Reel 5897, Frame 269-321)
      - Notes on Russia and Russian Artists, n.d. (Box 3, Reel 5897, Frame 322-384)
      - Notes on Russian Art, n.d. (Box 3, Reel 5897, Frame 385-540)
      - Notes, Miscellaneous, n.d., (2 folders) (Box 3, Reel 5897, Frame 541-845)
    - Translations (Box 3, Reel 5897)
      - Auguste, Compte Jean Marie Mathias Philippe, "Villiers de l'Isle Adam," translated by Louis Lozowick, n.d. (Box 3, Reel 5897, Frame 846-894)
      - El Lissitsky. "Concerning the Mohilev Synagogue Reminiscences," n.d. (Box 3, Reel 5897, Frame 895-904)
  - By Other Authors, 1911-1949, 3.2:
    - Artists' Statements (A-Z), n.d. (Box 3, Reel 5897, Frame 906-915)
    - Chapter Outlines by Various Authors, Approved by Editorial Committee, 1930-1931 (Box 3, Reel 5897, Frame 916-945)
    - Beyer, Oskar, "Architektur in Eisen und Beten," n.d. (Box 3, Reel 5897, Frame 948-962)
    - Burnham, B. "Art as Weapon," n.d. (Box 3, Reel 5897, Frame 963-971)
    - Ferdman, Joe. "Portrait of an Artist" (poem about Lozowick), 1949 (Box 3, Reel 5897, Frame 972-973)
    - George. "Modern Drawing," n.d. (Box 3, Reel 5897, Frame 974-979)
    - Kravchenko, A. I. "Soviet Pictorial Art-The Artist, the Art School and the Public," n.d. (Box 3, Reel 5897, Frame 980-991)
    - Marinetti, F. F. War Account, 1911 (Box 3, Reel 5897, Frame 992-1028)
    - Schwarz, Karl. "Modern Art in Palestine," n.d. (Box 3, Reel 5897, Frame 1029-1051)
    - Workers of a Soviet Tractor Factory, "Letter to Artists," n.d. (Box 3, Reel 5897, Frame 1052-1056)
    - Unknown. "Louis Lozowick" (poem), n.d. (Box 3, Reel 5897, Frame 1057-1058)
    - Unknown. Untitled Article about the Problem of Minority Nationalities in Europe, n.d. (Box 3, Reel 5897, Frame 1059-1070)
    - Unknown. Untitled Play (title pg. missing); Paper on Duke Richard of Portland [pg. 1 missing]; Unidentified Text in (Yiddish), n.d. (Box 3, Reel 5897, Frame 1071-1101)
- Business Records, 1929-1973, Series 4:; (Box 3; 0.25 linear ft.; Reel 5897-5898)
  Among the Lozowick's business records is an extensive file (originally maintained in loose leaf binders) arranged by name of museum, gallery, institution, or event. These record names of paintings and prints loaned for exhibition or consigned for sale, with sales and return dates noted. Filed along with Lozowick's handwritten lists are miscellaneous printed items relating to various exhibitions and benefit auctions/sales. Additional business records consist of receipts for expenses and income derived from commercial work, lectures, and writing.
  - Business Records, A-Z (removed from loose leaf binders), 1930s-1973, (4 folders) (Box 3, Reel 5897, Frame 1103-1455)
  - Receipts for Business Expenses, 1931-1973, n.d. (Box 3, Reel 5898, Frame 13-39)
  - Receipts for Commercial Art Work, Lectures, Writings, and Reproduction Fees, 1929-1962, n.d. (Box 3, Reel 5898, Frame 40-67)
  - Receipts for Personal Expenses, 1933-1968, n.d. (Box 3, Reel 5898, Frame 69-78)
  - WPA Arts Program, Daily Report, September 17, 1940 (Box 3, Reel 5898, Frame 79-81)
- Organizations, 1930-1972, Series 5:; (Box 4; 0.4 linear ft.; Reel 5898)
  This series consists mainly of printed material, unpublished notes and writings, and miscellaneous items relating to organizations and groups of interest to Lozowick. Of particular interest his files relating to the American Artists' Congress and the John Reed Club. Lozowick served as an officer of each organization and among his papers are some of their minutes, reports, and official correspondence. Among the American Artists' Congress Correspondence, 1936-1940, are letters from Ralton Crawford, Peppino Mangravite, and Max Weber. The John Reed Club's correspondence, 1931-1935, includes letters from John Steuart Curry and Walter Quirt.
  - All America Magazine, 1930, n.d. (Box 4, Reel 5898, Frame 84-94)
  - American Artists' Congress (Box 4, Reel 5898)
    - Constitution and By-Laws, n.d. (Box 4, Reel 5898, Frame 95-108)
    - Correspondence (Louis Lozowick, Executive Secretary), 1936-1940, n.d. (Box 4, Reel 5898, Frame 109-222)
    - Minutes, 1935-1939 (Box 4, Reel 5898, Frame 223-303)
    - Notes, n.d. (Box 4, Reel 5898, Frame 304-312)